

#### CONTACT ME AT

- 3-5-118/2/3, Krishna Nagar, Hyderguda, Attapur, Hyderabad, Telangana State, India.
- skiran017@gmail.com
- +91 8789680086
- in <u>@skiran017</u>
- https://skiran017.github.io/portfolio/

### SKILLS SUMMARY

- •••• React / Redux
- ●●●● Webpack & Babel
- ●●●● NodeJS MongoDB
- •••• HTML5, CSS3 & JS
- •••• MATLAB CATIA FEM
- •••• Staff and User Management & Training

#### AWARDS RECEIVED

- Best Performer of the Month (March 2019)
- Research paper published:contact stresses distribution on
  Plunge-Cutting into a Steel
  Workpiece (Apr 2018).
- Research paper published:-Calculation of Contact Stresses distribution during titanium alloy cutting (Apr 2018).

# SAI KIRAN SABAVATH

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a Mechanical Engineer graduate, research enthusiast, Front-End developer who loves to work on React, React-Native and basically with any other tech in JS Ecosystem. Other than that I also enjoy cooking, playing soccer and chess.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Arc Dev - Agency Website

React with MUI - Github - Live

An Agency Responsive Website made using React and MUI

# Infinite Image Gallery

React with Unsplash API- Github - Live

• Image Gallery with infinite scroll built on top of Unsplash API

# **Moving Sprite**

React and Canvas Game - Github - Live

React and Canvas implementation of Moving Sprite

#### **Contact Keeper**

MERN Stack - Github - Live

 Made a full stack app using React, Node, Mongodb, Express JWT to store and manage contacts

### GitHub Finder

React and Context API - Github - Live

• Built whole flux like system using Context API and Hooks

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Software Engineer

Dhan Tech Labs India Pvt. Ltd | Jan 2021 - Present

- I build and maintain the frontend architecture of the products and various internal tools at Dhan.
- I lead Frontend Engineering Team.
- I write Tests to ensure quality of the code being delivered.
- I do performance audits and optimizations to ensure great experience.
- Tech stack: React/Redux, Redux-Saga, React-Native, Ionic-React, Webpack, Babel, TypeScript, Yarn/NPM, Material-UI, Styled-Components, Zustand, MonoRepo.

#### TRON SME

Amazon(AVOC) | Mar 2020 - Jan 2021

- Team lead and Mentor of 30+ Analysts.
- Analyzing the data of inbound volume and to make sure enough workforce is available to handle the volume

# **TRON Analyst**

Amazon(AVOC) | Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

- Analysing visual data and feeding it to the Machine.
- Got promoted to TRON Subject Matter Expert

#### EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

# Tomsk Polytechnic University, Tomsk, Russia

Mechanical engineering | Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

- Specialization in Design and Manufacturing technologies
- ECTS: 4.63/5

# Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, Czech Republic

Semester Exchange | Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

- CATIA, MATLAB, FEM
- ECTS: 4/5

# Little Flower Junior College

Senior Secondary High School | June 2011 - April 2013

- Maths, Physics, Chemistry as Primary subjects
- Grade: A (78%)

## Little Flower School

High School | CBSE | April 2011

• CGPA: 8.6/10